

MAURICIO JAVIER FRIAS ORTIZ

CONTACT

314 894 8363 604 5031957

mauriciofrias22@hotmail.com

Medellín, Cra 58 # 3 sur 43 Barrio Cristo rey

WHO AM I

Highly motivated, customeroriented IT Technician with 18 years of experience and software developer with 4 months of working experience using the Python language with the Django framework.

I am a passionate and driven person with a strong foundation in programming logic and determination to а grow as eager developer, I am contribute my skills and continue learning from more experienced mentors.

In addition to work experience, I have developed some personal projects where I have been able to practice my front-end knowledge with React.

EXPERIENCE

La Chismosa Taqueria | December 2023 – Currently

Restaurant Manager, Medellin - Antioquia

Tasks:

- Personnel management, Personnel schedules, Purchase orders management.
- Customer service, sales, goals achievement.

Online Helpers | June 2023 - November 2023

Chat Customer Service Associate, Remote Freelance

Tasks:

- Managing inquiries from customers in English through chat.
- Effectively helve customers queries with the scripts provided.

Macondo Gastro - Bar | April 2021 - May 2023

Restaurant Manager, Cartagena - Bolívar

Tasks:

- Personnel management, Personnel schedules, Purchase orders management.
- Personnel payroll, Customer service, Sales, Goals achievement.

Klever 4 Solutions | November 2020 - March 2021

Junior Python Developer, Medellin (Remote)

Tasks:

- Developed and maintained various applications using python and related technologies.
- Collaborated with cross-functional teams to design, develop and deploy software solutions.
- Write server-side code to handle data processing, business logic and database interactions.
- Troubleshot and resolved technical issues in a timely manner.
- Use version control systems to manage changes to the code base.

Luxury Rentals | March 2018 - October 2019

Limo Service Driver, Cartagena - Bolivar

Tasks:

- Safely transport of clients from one location to another in a comfortable and stylish manner.
- Perform routine inspections to make sure that the limo is clean, well maintained and fully stocked with necessary amenities such as drinks and snacks.
- Anticipate and respond to the client needs.

Home Service | April 2016 - February 2018

Computer Technician, Cartagena - Bolívar

Tasks

- Diagnosed and resolved Hardware and software issues for bothPC and laptops.
- Provided technical support to customers' in-person, via e-mail and phone.
- Performed system backups and data recovery procedures.

PERSONAL SKILLS

- Problem Solving
- Flexibility
- Assertive Communication
- Creativity
- Empathy
- Responsibility

PROFESSIONAL SKILLS

- Teamwork
- Customer Service
- Continuous Learning
- SCRUM
- Git
- Visual Studio Code
- HTML
- CSS
- REACT

Avis Car Rental | March 2015 - April 2016

Bilingual Counter Assistant, Cartagena - Bolívar

Tasks:

- Provide excellent service to the customers, addressing their needs and concerns, and ensuring a positive experience with the company.
- Assist customers with making reservations, answering questions about rental rates, and providing information about the rental process.
- Perform thorough inspections to vehicles before renting them to minimize any issues or concerns that customers may have during their rental period.

EDUCATION

December 2021 | Barranquilla - Atlántico (Virtual)

Diploma of programming skills with emphasis on web development

Universidad del Norte (MisionTic 2022 Program)

December 2021 | Barranquilla - Atlántico (Virtual)

Courses:

Programming Fundamentals Basic Programming Software Development

Universidad del Norte (MisionTic 2022 Program)

November 2020 | Cartagena – Bolívar (Virtual)

Courses:

Linear Data Structures Code Foundations Learn How to Code Python Developer

Udemy (Virtual Platform)

May 2004 | Cartagena - Bolívar

Basic Accounting Course

Sena

November 2002 | Cartagena - Bolívar

Computer Maintenance Course

Unitep

August 2002 | Cartagena - Bolívar

Proficiency in the English Language

Centro Colombo Americano